Guide to the John D. Mattox Papers
John D. Mattox Papers
- North Carolina State University Photographs
  - Charlotte Womble, Old Farm & Home (neg), 1971 (Box 5)
  - Air Force R.O.T.C. Glee Club (neg), Feb 22, 1955 (Box 5)
  - Lynn Tullock holding lambs (neg), May 3, 1963 (Box 5)
  - Lynn Tullock holding lambs (Print), May 3, 1963 (Box 5)
  - Visual Aids Office Mary Lou Philips at film splicer (neg), Aug 31, 1959 (Box 5)
  - Elevator repair on roof, Ricks Hall (neg), Nov 3, 1967 (Box 5)
  - NC State Campus Road Scene, Back of Coliseum (neg), 1952 (Box 5)
  - Miss Glynne Hodge, Industrial Arts Office with dogwood (neg), April 18, 1956 (Box 5)
  - Miss Glynne Hodge, Industrial Arts Office with dogwood (Print), April 18, 1956 (Box 5)
  - Rudolph Pate & wife at Chancellor reception (neg), 1953 (Box 5)
  - (Contact Sheets) Unidentified Banquet (Print) (Box 5)
  - Mrs. Katherine McKimmon (neg), Dec 18, 1957 (Box 5)
  - Mrs. Katherine McKimmon (Print), Dec 18, 1957 (Box 5)
  - Altrusa Event(?) (Print) (Box 5)
  - Campus Scenes (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Class of 1933 reunion, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - John Mattox, photographer (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Music lyrics and sheet music (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Portraits (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Publications with Mattox photos (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Retirement Events (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - R.O.T.C. Glee Club (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Slides (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Slides (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Publication with Mattox Photos (Flatfolder 10)
- Miscellaneous Photographs
  This series contains miscellaneous portraits and landscapes.
  - Myrtle Meikels, Atlanta, Ga. (neg) (Box 4)
  - Ft. Todd Tobacco (neg), Aug 12, 1964 (Box 4)
  - Johnny & Anna Maria with dog (neg), Oct 1966 (Box 4)
  - Beverly (daughter of Elwood Horton) (neg), Dec 1970 (Box 4)
  - M.C. Todd; copies of thesis; old letters & deeds (neg), Sept 1951 (Box 4)
  - Gold Locket copies (Print), Aug 19, 1971 (Box 4)
  - Gold Locket copies (neg), Aug 19, 1971 (Box 4)
  - Raleigh Stamp Shop - Opening day (neg) (Box 4)
  - Nell Kennett, copy (Print), July 1965 (Box 4)
  - Nell Kennett, copy (neg), July 1965 (Box 4)
  - Pauline & Erdine Griffin, copy (neg), 1980 (Box 4)
  - Stamps copied (neg), Jan 30, 1976 (Box 4)
  - Sheet music and deed, copy (neg) (Box 4)
  - Sue and Curtis as children, copy (neg), Jan 1953 (Box 4)
  - Two little girls (neg), May 1982 (Box 4)
  - Two little girls (Print), May 1982 (Box 4)
  - Sybil's Great Grandmother, copy (Print), Aug 1980 (Box 4)
  - Miss Ruth Wilson, copy (neg), Feb 26, 1970 (Box 4)
  - Milton Croom - Home & Farm (neg), Aug 20, 1970 (Box 4)
  - Cal Tone Paint Plant, Raleigh, N.C, interiors, mills, stock racks, etc. (neg), Feb 18, 1963 (Box 4)
  - Luther Ledford & wife portrait (Print), Oct 1966 (Box 4)
  - Luther Ledford & wife portrait (neg), Oct 1966 (Box 4)
  - Luther Ledford portrait (neg), Sept 13, 1953 (Box 4)
  - Jasper & Nita Thomas (neg), Aug 1980 (Box 4)
  - Bill Parish and father (neg), Feb 2, 1971 (Box 4)
  - Jimmy Batton portrait (neg), June 5, 1964 (Box 4)
  - Martha Parrish portrait (neg), Jan 30, 1969 (Box 4)
  - Martha Parrish portrait (Print), Jan 30, 1969 (Box 4)
  - Elgie Painter & wife, Carolyn (daughter) (Print), Dec 6, 1965 (Box 4)
  - Elgie Painter & wife (neg), Dec 6, 1965 (Box 4)
  - Miley Johnson daughter at graduation (neg) (Box 4)
  - John and Ann Todd passport photos (neg), Aug 22, 1966 (Box 4)
  - Jim Parrish portrait (neg), May 1968 (Box 4)
  - Scott Smith portrait (neg), Jan 31, 1960 (Box 4)
  - Scott Smith portrait (Print), Jan 31, 1960 (Box 4)
  - Scott Smith, son of Hazel Smith (neg), 1958 (Box 4)
  - Scott Smith, son of Hazel Smith (Print), 1958 (Box 4)
  - Lee Knott portrait (neg), Oct 1968 (Box 4)
  - Lee Knott portrait (Print), Oct 1968 (Box 4)
  - Prof E.W. Winkler, old home place (neg), Feb 1981 (Box 4)
  - Mrs. Lesley Brondwell(?) (neg), March 1969 (Box 4)
  - Mrs. Fowlkes(?) (neg), April 4, 1954 (Box 4)
  - Mrs. Fowlkes(?) (Print), April 4, 1954 (Box 4)
  - Warren Dean & Margaret, baby portrait (neg) (Box 4)
  - Dick Brantley & wife (neg), Feb 9, 1971 (Box 4)
  - Dr. Lesley Brodwell portrait (neg), May 1968 (Box 4)
  - Miss Horton (neg), about 1972 (Box 4)
  - Mary Baptist (Print) (Box 4)
  - Mr. Baxley and brother in Navy uniform (neg), 1974 (Box 4)
  - Bill Roberts portrait (Print), Aug 27, 1962 (Box 4)
  - Bill Roberts portrait (neg), Aug 27, 1962 (Box 4)
  - Elbert Holmes (neg), May 7, 1964 (Box 4)
  - Dr. Landis Bennett portrait (neg), 1957 (Box 4)
  - Pauline Scarbro portrait (neg), March 27, 1966 (Box 4)
  - Betsy Andrews portraits (neg), May 29, 1958 (Box 4)
  - Betsy Andrews portraits (Print), May 29, 1958 (Box 4)
  - G.E. Store, New Bern, N.C. (neg), 1959 (Box 4)
  - Jim Higgins Wedding at Willis House, Jim & Laurie, Greenville, S.C. (neg), June 15, 1956 (Box 4)
  - Bell Tower on Will Mattox farm, Bucky (age 9) and Rex Hinton (father) (neg), March 1955 (Box 4)
  - President Johnson House (neg), Aug 29, 1957 (Box 4)
  - Griffin Pond on Pool Road (neg), Jan 17, 1953 (Box 4)
  - Dulcimer (neg), Aug 22, 1966 (Box 4)
  - Jim Higgins (neg) (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Unidentified Photographs
  This series contains a small number of unidentified photographs, including originals and copies of older photographic types including tintypes and cartes de visite from the late nineteenth century.
  - Unidentified Women (neg) (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous Unidentified Portrait (neg) (Box 4)
  - Unidentified Portrait of ladies outside (tintype), circa 1900 (Box 4)
  - Unidentified Portrait of ladies outside (neg), circa 1900 (Box 4)
  - Copy of Unidentified Letter (neg) (Box 4)
  - Young man in Oval (neg) (Box 4)
  - Women standing next to car (neg) (Box 4)
  - Old tintype portrait (tintype), circa 1860s (Box 4)
  - Old tintype portrait (Print), circa 1860s (printed: March 9, 1961) (Box 4)
  - Old tintype portrait (neg), circa 1860s (Printed: March 9, 1961) (Box 4)
  - Unidentified old pictures (tintype), circa late 1800s (Box 4)
  - Unidentified old pictures (tintype), circa 1800s (Box 4)
  - Unidentified old pictures (cartes de visite) (Print), circa 1800s (Box 4)
  - Unidentified old pictures (cartes de visite) (Print), circa late 1800s (Box 4)
  - Unidentified woman, original carte de visite, From Fratelli d'Alessandri, Roma (Print) (Box 4)
  - Unidentified woman, small print from Rome, Italy (Print) (Box 4)
  - Unidentified woman, small print from Rome, Italy (neg) (Box 4)
  - Old Pictures (Print), circa late 1800s (Box 5)
  - Old Pictures (Print), circa late 1800s (Box 5)
  - Unidentified (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Unidentified (Flatfolder 10)
- Wedding Photographs
  This series contains bridal portraits and photographs of wedding receptions.
  - Dorothy Knott Cakecutting & Wedding (neg), Sept 10-11, 1954 (Box 5)
  - Patricia Murphy Wedding Dress (neg), Oct 1966 (Box 5)
  - Proc Dean Wedding, Cakecutting & Wedding (Print), Nov 30 & Dec 1, 1962 (Box 5)
  - Proc Dean Wedding, Cakecutting & Wedding (neg), Nov 30 & Dec 1, 1962 (Box 5)
  - Nell Richardson/Duke Wedding (neg), Jan 1, 1955 (Box 5)
  - Cecilia Parsons (neg), Sept 1969 (Box 5)
  - Jeannette Horton Wedding (Print), May 27, 1952 (Box 5)
  - Jeannette Horton Wedding (neg), May 27, 1952 (Box 5)
  - Patricia Murphy Wedding Candids (neg), Nov 1966 (Box 5)
  - Mrs. Veasy Anniversary (neg), Aug 31, 1952 (Box 5)
  - John Curtis - Church Reception (neg), July 1962 (Box 5)
  - Mr. & Mrs. Welborn Todd 50th Anniversary (neg) (Box 5)
  - Yuonne Glover Hinnant (neg), Nov 1963 (Box 5)
  - Yuonne Glover Hinnant (Print), Nov 1963 (Box 5)
  - Anne Knott Wedding (neg), June 1967 (Box 5)
  - Frances Ledford Wedding (neg), Oct 14, 1960 (Box 5)
  - Mrs. Richard Snowden (neg), May 1969 (Box 5)
  - Mrs. Richard Snowden Wedding Formals (Print), May 1969 (Box 5)
  - Sharon Bond (Fred Bond father) (neg), Nov 12, 1969 (Box 5)
  - Sherron Rice Wedding Formal (Print) (Box 5)
  - Sherron Rice Wedding Formal (neg) (Box 5)
  - Clara Johnson Wedding Portrait (Print), March 1971 (Box 5)
  - Clara Johnson Wedding Portrait (neg), March 1971 (Box 5)
  - Unidentified Wedding (neg) (Box 5)
  - Unidentified Wedding Receptions (Print) (Box 5)
  - Kay & Fay Sanderford (neg) (Box 5)
  - Kay & Fay Sanderford (18 year old twins), Wendell, N.C. (Mrs. Joe E. Johnson, mother) (Print) (Box 5)
  - Mrs. Wyatt Dean's brother, Wedding at hospital church (neg) (Box 5)
  - Annie Sue's Wedding (neg) (Box 5)
  - Virginia Lee Price - reception at Christian Church (neg), Oct 5, 1962 (Box 5)
  - Yuonne Glover Wedding (Print), Nov 9, 1963 (Box 5)
  - Yuonne Glover Wedding (neg), Nov 9, 1963 (Box 5)
  - Dorothy Knott Cakecutting & Wedding (Print), Sept 10-11, 1954 (Box 5)
  - Bridal Portraits (Flatfolder 10)
- World War II Photographs
  This series contains various photographs which document Mattox’s service in Europe during World War II. Locations include Holland, Belgium, England, Germany, and France. The photographs portray Mattox alone or with other soldiers or native Europeans. Several items are of the glee club and band, of which Mattox was a member. Other items include postcards and a miniature set of souvenir photographs of Paris.
  - Miscellaneous (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Postcards (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Postcards (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Paris Photo Set (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Papers
  This series contains news clippings, correspondence, business cards, awards, brochures, grade reports, and other personal papers belonging to Mattox.
  - Miscellaneous (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - News Clippings (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Travel Brochures (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Rolled Negatives (Box 11)
  This series contains rolled 35 mm negatives, some of which have corresponding prints elsewhere in the collection.